♪You crossed the sea of ​​stars and came with light♪
♪เธอข้ามผ่านหมู่ดวงดาว มาพร้อมกับแสงสว่าง♪
♪My heart is like the dust, and I couldn't bear to stain the hemline♪
♪หัวใจฉันเปรียบเหมือนฝุ่น ไม่อยากแปดเปื้อนกระโปรงของเธอ♪
♪To love in a different way, the fireworks are in the stars' good graces♪
♪ความรักที่ไม่เหมือนใคร ดอกไม้ไฟที่ดวงดาวยังชายตามอง♪
♪I turn around and realize that my heart is empty♪
♪หันกลับมาจึงเข้าใจ ดวงใจได้ขาดหายไป♪
♪I miss the overflowing galaxy surging into the sea♪
♪ความคิดถึงท่วมท้นจักรวาล เอ่อล้นจนเต็มท้องทะเล♪
♪Even the fireworks desire to give the stars a future♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟอยากเป็นที่พึ่งพิงให้ดวงดาว♪
♪As long as you are around♪
♪ขอเพียงแค่มีเธออยู่♪
♪Even the fireworks fear to bloom♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟกลัวจะสว่างแล้วดับสูญ♪
♪Looking at you, the light in your eyes dimmed♪
♪มองดูนัยน์ตาของเธอ แสงไฟค่อย ๆ เลือนหาย♪
♪I laughed at myself and that I deserve it ♪
♪ทำได้แต่สมน้ำหน้าตัวเอง♪
♪My heart skips a beat, but I'm afraid I'm not worthy of the future that you desire♪
♪ฉันใจสั่น♪
=Episode 22=
=ตอนที่ 22=
It's snowing!
หิมะตกแล้ว
Here used to
เมื่อก่อนบอร์ดนี่
have your photos all the time.
ติดรูปนายเต็มไปหมด
What competitions you entered,
ลงแข่งรายการไหนบ้าง
what awards you got etc.
ได้รางวัลอะไรมาก็ติดหมด
Do you still remember
ที่ฉันพูดกับนาย
what I said to you
ตอนอยู่บ้านพี่หลิง
at Ms. Ling's house?
นายยังจำได้ไหม
I said,
ฉันบอกว่า
you'll be
ต่อไปนายจะกลายเป็น
an amazing aerospace engineer in the future.
นักวิทยาศาสตร์อวกาศที่เก่งมาก ๆ
When that happens,
ถึงตอนนั้น
as your classmate,
ในฐานะเพื่อนของนาย
I will feel very proud.
ฉันคงรู้สึกเป็นเกียรติมาก
I remember.
จำได้สิ
But actually, it's not like that.
แต่ความจริงไม่ใช่อย่างนั้นหรอก
It's not as your classmate.
ไม่ใช่แค่ในฐานะเพื่อนของนาย
Then, what is it?
แล้วเป็นอะไร
Actually...
ความจริง
ever since last time,
ตั้งแต่สมัยก่อน
I have
ฉันแอบคิดเพ้อฝัน
some weird imaginations.
ประหลาด ๆ
I'll tell you, but don't laugh at me.
ถ้าพูดออกมา นายห้ามหัวเราะฉันนะ
I imagined that after a long time,
ฉันคิดฝันไปว่าในอนาคตที่แสนไกล
during the school festival,
ในงานเลี้ยงโรงเรียน
you'll get invited back to school
นายในฐานะนักวิทยาศาสตร์อวกาศ
as a very reputable
ที่มีชื่อเสียง
aerospace engineer.
ได้รับเชิญมาที่โรงเรียน
And then...
แล้วก็
I'll be by your side.
มีฉันอยู่ข้าง ๆ
So Mr. Yu,
ดังนั้น อาจารย์อวี๋
you have to work hard.
นายต้องพยายามเข้านะ
I have high expectations of you.
ฉันคาดหวังกับนายนะ
Jingjing.
จิงจิง
I feel that sometimes
บางทีฉันคิดว่า
you're a bit blind when it comes to me.
เธอมองฉันดีเกินไป
Back in high school,
สมัยเรียนม.ปลาย
I used to think that I was very smart too.
ฉันคิดว่าตัวเองฉลาด
Only when I went out, I realized that
พอเรียนจบมาถึงได้รู้
it's a vast world out there
ว่าโลกนี้มันกว้างใหญ่นัก
and how insignificant I am.
ฉันก็แค่คนตัวเล็ก ๆ
I wasn't as much of a genius
ไม่ได้เก่งกาจอย่างที่
as I thought I was.
ตัวเองเคยคิดไว้แต่แรก
My IQ is also far from
ไอคิวฉันยังห่างไกล
being in the first tier.
กับทีมแถวหน้าสุด
The...
ทีม
The first tier you mean is...
ทีมแถวหน้าสุดที่นายพูดถึงคือ
Qian Xuesen,
เฉียนเสวียเซิน
Sergei Korolev,
โคโรเลฟ
Theodore von Kármán.
ฟอน คาร์มาน
It's okay. You can continue.
ไม่เป็นไร พูดต่อเถอะ
But I'll work hard.
แต่ฉันจะพยายาม
I think I can.
ฉันคิดว่าฉันทำได้
I realized you might gravitate towards BDS.
ฉันคิดว่าเธอมีแนวโน้มจะเป็น BDS
What's BDS?
BDS คืออะไร
Baidu-search it yourself.
เสิร์ชไป่ตู้เองสิ
How dare you say this to me?
นายกล้าพูดแบบนี้กับฉันเหรอ
We're closing soon.
จะปิดประตูแล้วนะ
♪My heart is like the dust, and I couldn't bear to stain the hemline♪
ขอบคุณครับลุง
No problem.
อื้ม ๆ
Thank you, sir!
ขอบคุณค่ะลุง
You're welcome.
อื้ม
You...
หนู
You're that...
หนูคือ
Yes, I'm that!
หนูคือคนคนนั้นเองค่ะ
Thank you for letting us in.
ขอบคุณคุณลุงที่ให้เข้ามานะคะ
Happy Lunar New Year! We'll get going.
สุขสันต์วันตรุษจีนค่ะ พวกเราไปก่อนนะคะ
- Happy Lunar New Year!
สุขสันต์วันตรุษจีน สุขสันต์วันตรุษจีน
(Yixing No.1 Middle School) Come back often!
(โรงเรียนมัธยมอี๋ซิง 1 แห่งมณฑลเจียงซู) กลับมาเยี่ยมบ่อย ๆ ล่ะ
Okay!
ค่ะ
♪I miss the overflowing galaxy surging into the sea♪
♪ความคิดถึงท่วมท้นจักรวาล เอ่อล้นจนเต็มท้องทะเล♪
♪Even the fireworks desire to give the stars a future♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟอยากเป็นที่พึ่งพิงให้ดวงดาว♪
♪As long as you are around♪
♪ขอเพียงแค่มีเธออยู่♪
♪Even the fireworks fear to bloom♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟกลัวจะสว่างแล้วดับสูญ♪
♪Looking at you, the light in your eyes dimmed♪
♪มองดูนัยน์ตาของเธอ แสงไฟค่อย ๆ เลือนหาย♪
♪I look forward to every second♪
♪เฝ้ารอคอยทุกวินาที♪
♪I can run toward the future with you ♪
♪ที่ฉันจะได้จับมือเธอพุ่งทะยานไป♪
♪Regardless of everything♪
♪สู่อนาคตโดยไม่แคร์สิ่งใด♪
I think my parents are playing mahjong now.
พ่อแม่ฉันคงเล่นไพ่นกกระจอกอยู่
Let's stop here.
ส่งฉันแค่นี้ก็พอ
Go.
กลับไปเถอะ
Goodnight.
กู๊ดไนท์
If I want to keep our relationship
ถ้าช่วงนี้
a secret from my parents for the time being,
ฉันปิดบังพ่อแม่เรื่องคบกับนาย
are you okay with that?
นายคงไม่ว่าอะไรใช่ไหม
Otherwise, it's pretty troublesome
ไม่งั้นคงถูกคนอื่นถามซ้ำ ๆ ซาก ๆ
to keep getting asked about it.
ฉันขี้เกียจตอบ
How long
ช่วงนี้
is 'for the time being'?
นานแค่ไหนเหรอ
Until someone spills it?
จนกว่าจะมีคนเอามาแฉ
I think this way
ฉันว่าแบบนี้
they might get surprised.
พ่อกับแม่คงเซอร์ไพรส์ดี
Our parents might not think the same...
พ่อแม่เราคงไม่คิดอย่างนั้น
When I send you back to Shanghai tomorrow,
งั้นพรุ่งนี้ตอนส่งเธอกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้
what identity should I adopt then?
จะให้ใช้ฐานะอะไร
Ex-classmate.
เพื่อนม.ปลาย
Would your parents believe it?
พ่อแม่เธอจะเชื่อเหรอ
But if you just appear plainly
ถ้าอยู่ดี ๆ
out of no where,
นายโผล่ไปละก็
they'll definitely suspect something.
พ่อแม่ต้องสงสัยแน่
Then,
งั้นฉัน
let me make up a story first.
จะแต่งเรื่องขึ้นมาก่อน
Let me think.
ขอคิดแป๊บ
I'll say that...
ฉันจะบอกว่า
I'll say that the driver can't come tomorrow,
ฉันจะบอกว่าพรุ่งนี้คนขับรถมาไม่ได้
so I'll
ฉันก็เลย
drive back to Shanghai myself.
ต้องขับรถกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้เอง
You have a driver's license?
เธอมีใบขับขี่เหรอ
Of course, I have.
มีสิ
I know how to drive.
ฉันขับรถเป็นนะ
Don't interrupt me.
นายอย่าเพิ่งขัดจังหวะ
Nonetheless, my parents
ถึงยังไงพ่อแม่ฉัน
will definitely object
ก็ไม่ยอมให้ฉัน
to the idea of me driving back to Shanghai on my own.
ขับรถกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้คนเดียวหรอก
And then, just so happens,
แล้วฉันก็จะทำเป็นบังเอิญเห็น
I come across a message in our high school chatroom
กลุ่มแชทเพื่อนม.ปลาย
that someone is going back to Shanghai
บอกมีคนจะกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้
and can bring me along.
พาฉันกลับไปด้วยได้พอดี
After laying out the backstories,
ฉันกรุยทางไว้แบบนี้
my parents
พ่อแม่ฉัน
definitely won't suspect anything anymore.
ไม่มีทางสงสัยแน่นอน
What do you think?
นายคิดว่ายังไง
What's that face?
สีหน้าแบบนี้คืออะไร
Nothing.
ไม่มีอะไร
I just suddenly remembered about the time
จู่ ๆ ก็นึกขึ้นได้เรื่องที่เธอ
you tricked me into repairing the purifier.
หลอกฉันไปซ่อมเครื่องฟอกอากาศ
Not only
คุณเฉียวของพวกเรา
is our Ms. Qiao an actor,
ไม่ใช่แค่นักแสดง
you even know
แต่ยังมี
how to make up stories on the spot.
ความสามารถในการเสกบทละคร
As someone
ในฐานะคนที่จะ
who will be spending
ใช้ชีวิตที่เหลือ
the longest time with you for the rest of your life,
ร่วมกับเธอมากกว่าใคร ๆ
I think
ฉันคิดว่า
I need to prepare myself mentally.
ฉันคงต้องเตรียมใจไว้
You look very reluctant.
นายไม่เต็มใจใช่ไหม
Why would I?
เปล่าสักหน่อย
Then, I need to work hard.
งั้นฉันจะพยายามเต็มที่
Can't have you get ready for nothing.
เพื่อไม่ให้ความพยายามนายต้องสูญเปล่า
Don't work too hard.
เธอไม่ต้องพยายามมากหรอก
Are you getting scared?
กลัวเหรอ
Not to that extent.
ไม่ถึงกับกลัว
You give it a try.
เธอลองดูสิ
Hello!
ฮัลโหล
How's your elopement going? Happy?
หนีกันไปสองคนมีความสุขไหม
(Yu Tu)
(อวี๋ถู)
It's more than half an hour now,
เกือบชั่วโมงแล้วนะ
and he's still not back home yet.
ยังไม่ถึงบ้านอีก
(Have you sent Peipei back home?)
(ส่งเพ่ยเพ่ยถึงบ้านหรือยัง)
(Are you home yet?)
(ถึงบ้านหรือยัง)
(I'm back home!)
(ฉันถึงบ้านแล้ว)
(Did you just reach?)
(เพิ่งถึงเหรอ)
(No, I've been back for some time already.)
(ไม่ ถึงได้สักพักแล้ว)
(My husband kept asking me)
(ถูกสามีตามจิก)
(who's the person who sent me back.)
(ว่าคนที่มาส่งเป็นใคร)
(Your class had)
(ห้องเธอมีเพื่อน)
(such a good-looking classmate etc.)
(หน้าตาดีขนาดนี้ด้วยเหรอ)
(It's tiring when your husband)
(ผู้หญิงที่ถูกสามีตามหึง)
(cares so much about you.)
(มันเหนื่อยนะยะ)
(Read.)
(อ้อ...อ่านแล้ว)
(How about Yu Tu?)
(อวี๋ถูล่ะ)
(Yu Tu is not back yet?)
(ยังไม่ถึงบ้านเหรอ)
(That can't be.)
(เป็นไปไม่ได้)
(From my house to his,)
(จากบ้านฉันถึงบ้านเขา)
(it should only take the cab)
(นั่งแท็กซี่ไป)
(a few minutes.)
(ไม่กี่นาทีก็ถึงแล้ว)
(Let me ask him.)
(ฉันจะถามเขาดู)
(WeChat: One unread message.)
(มีข้อความใหม่ 1 ข้อความ)
(I'll call you in a short while.)
(เดี๋ยวโทรไปหานะ)
(I'm reporting to my mom now.)
(ฉันกำลังเปิดใจกับแม่อยู่)
Reporting?
เปิดใจกับแม่เหรอ
(Okay.)
(โอเค)
(I'm done reporting.)
(เรียบร้อยแล้ว )
(Jingjing.)
(จิงจิง)
(Are you asleep?)
(นอนหรือยัง)
(Goodnight.)
(กู๊ดไนท์)
(Good morning.)
(มอร์นิ่ง)
(Yu Tu)
(อวี๋ถู : จิงจิง นอนหรือยัง กู๊ดไนท์ มอร์นิ่ง)
You woke me up.
เสียงดังจนฉันตื่นเลย
You haven't got up yet?
ยังไม่ลุกจากเตียงอีกเหรอ
Back then, I'd be at your house at 9 AM.
เมื่อก่อนตอนเก้าโมงฉันก็ถึงบ้านเธอแล้ว
It's Lunar New Year.
ตรุษจีนปีใหม่แล้ว
Can't I just sleep in a while longer?
ให้ฉันนอนต่ออีกหน่อยไม่ได้เหรอ
My bad.
ฉันผิดเอง
I know it now.
ทีหลังไม่ทำแบบนี้อีกแล้ว
What did you mean when you said that
เมื่อวานที่นายรายงานแม่
you were reporting to your mom last night?
เรื่องที่เปิดใจมันคืออะไรเหรอ
It was just my mom asking me
แม่ฉันถามว่า
why am I going to Shanghai on the first day of Lunar New Year,
วันตรุษจีนไปเซี่ยงไฮ้
and who I met last night.
แล้วก็คนที่เจอเมื่อคืนเป็นใคร
But...
แต่มี
Someone decided to keep this from our parents.
คนบางคนไม่ยอมให้บอกพ่อแม่
So, I could only say that
ฉันเลยบอกได้แค่ว่า
it was a pretty girl.
เป็นผู้หญิงสวยคนหนึ่ง
And I didn't get the girl.
แถมฉันยังจีบไม่ติดด้วย
You seemed to have built
ภาพลักษณ์ฉันที่นายสร้างขึ้นมา
a rather bad image of me.
จะดูไม่น่าประทับใจเท่าไรนะ
Like someone
แบบว่า
who neither approves nor rejects.
เป็นพวกก้ำ ๆ กึ่ง ๆ ไม่ชัดเจน
Your mom would definitely
แม่นายต้องมองว่าฉัน
have a bad impression of me.
เป็นคนไม่ดีแน่เลย
I didn't consider things thoroughly.
ฉันคิดไม่รอบคอบเอง
How about this?
เอาอย่างนี้ไหม
Next time, we can tell her that
คราวหน้าฉันจะบอกแม่ว่า
I didn't get the girl whom I met last night
คนที่เจอตอนตรุษจีนกับเมื่อคืนวาน
and on the first day of New Year.
ฉันจีบไม่ติด
Ms. Qiao
ส่วนคุณเฉียว
is my new love interest.
เป็นแฟนใหม่ของฉัน
That'll only make me look bad.
แบบนี้ฉันก็ขายหน้าสิ
I'm joking.
ล้อเล่นน่ะ
Don't worry about this.
ไม่ต้องห่วงเรื่องนี้หรอก
I'm not worried.
ฉันไม่ได้ห่วงสักหน่อย
Elderlies like me.
เพราะผู้ใหญ่ต่างชอบฉัน
She'll like me when she sees me.
แม่นายเห็นฉันต้องชอบฉันแน่
Are you still sleepy?
ยังง่วงรึเปล่า
Do you want to continue your sleep?
จะนอนต่อสักหน่อยไหม
Later, I'll need to
เดี๋ยวฉัน
go downstairs to clear the snow.
จะลงไปกวาดหิมะข้างล่าง
Clear the snow?
กวาดหิมะ
Yeah.
ใช่
Our area is a bit older.
คอนโดที่พวกเราอยู่มันเก่าแล้ว
It's not under any property management.
ไม่มีนิติคอยดูแลเป็นเรื่องเป็นราว
I'll just clear a bit from the road outside
ฉันจะกวาดถนนสักหน่อย
so that it's easier to walk.
คนอื่น ๆ จะได้เดินสะดวก
Okay then.
เอาสิ
I'll sleep a bit more.
งั้นฉันนอนต่อสักพักนะ
Why did you sigh all of a sudden?
นี่นายถอนหายใจทำไม
Nothing.
ไม่มีอะไรหรอก
I was just thinking about
แค่กำลังคิดว่า
when I can go to your place and clear the snow there.
เมื่อไรจะได้ไปกวาดหิมะที่บ้านเธอสักที
I want to sleep now.
ฉันจะนอนแล้ว
Don't wake me up.
อย่าโทรมากวนนะ
I'm hanging up now.
วางล่ะ
Dad! Mom!
พ่อคะ แม่คะ
Until what time did they play mahjong last night
เมื่อคืนเล่นไพ่กันถึงกี่โมงเนี่ย
that they're still sleeping now?
ป่านนี้ยังไม่ตื่นอีก
My memory is so good.
ความจำฉันดีนะเนี่ย
Hello, there.
นี่คุณ
I'd like to ask for direction.
ขอถามทางหน่อยสิคะ
I heard that there is
ได้ยินว่าที่อี๋ซิง
a very delicious beancurd shop in Yixing.
มีร้านขายเต้าฮวยอร่อยอยู่เจ้าหนึ่ง
I don't know the way.
ไม่รู้จะไปยังไง
I'm hungry.
ฉันหิวแล้ว
Hey, I'm only asking for direction.
คุณคะ ฉันแค่ถามทางนะ
Isn't it a bit inappropriate to hug me like this?
มากอดฉันแบบนี้คงไม่ดีมั้ง
Didn't you say you were going to continue your sleep?
บอกจะนอนต่อไม่ใช่เหรอ
You're the one who woke me up.
ก็นายส่งข้อความเสียงดังนี่
I woke up
พอฉันตื่นมา
and saw that my parents were still in bed.
เห็นว่าพ่อแม่ฉันยังไม่ตื่น
I'm starving.
ฉันหิวไส้กิ่วแล้ว
Poor thing.
น่าสงสารจัง
Why aren't you asking me
ทำไมไม่ถามฉันล่ะ
how did I know that you lived here?
ว่ารู้ได้ไงว่านายอยู่ที่นี่
Let's go.
ไปกันเถอะ
I'll bring you to get breakfast.
ฉันพาเธอไปหาข้าวเช้ากิน
Yu Tu!
อวี๋ถู
Your grandaunt called to say that
ป้าเขาโทรมาบอกว่า
she'll be coming over later to have a meal.
เดี๋ยวจะมากินข้าวที่นี่
You go...
ลูกไป...
Your mom...
แม่นายมา
Oh, no.
แย่แล้ว
We're caught.
ถูกจับได้แล้ว
Yu Tu...
อวี๋ถู
This... This is...
นี่ ๆ นี่คือ...
Mom.
แม่
This is my...
นี่คือ...
Happy Lunar New Year.
คุณน้าคะ สุขสันต์วันตรุษจีนค่ะ
I am Yu Tu's girlfriend.
หนูเป็นแฟนอวี๋ถูค่ะ
My name is Qiao Jingjing.
ชื่อเฉียวจิงจิง
Girlfriend?
แฟนเหรอ
Qiao Jingjing.
เฉียวจิงจิง
The story's like this.
คุณน้าคะ คืออย่างนี้ค่ะ
Yu Tu and I
หนูกับอวี๋ถู
have been in a relationship for a very long time.
คบกันมานานแล้วค่ะ
But he always refused
แต่เขาไม่ยอมพาหนู
to bring me to see you.
มาเยี่ยมคุณพ่อคุณแม่
So, I have no choice
หนูก็เลย
but to come myself.
ต้องมาหาด้วยตัวเองน่ะค่ะ
Yes.
ใช่
It was me.
ผมเองครับ
I feel that...
ผมคิดว่า...
He feels that...
เขากลัวว่า
You might not like me.
คุณพ่อคุณแม่อาจจะไม่ชอบหนู
Who said that?
ใครบอกล่ะ
Yu Tu!
อวี๋ถู
What kind of nonsense is that?
ทำไมลูกพูดจาซี้ซั้วแบบนั้น
Jingjing.
จิงจิง
How can we
พวกเราจะไม่ชอบหนู
not like you?
ได้ยังไงกันล่ะ
I've never said anything like this.
น้าไม่เคยพูดแบบนี้สักหน่อย
He never mentioned anything to me.
เขาเองก็ไม่เคยพูดถึง
Mom...
แม่
So, he has never even mentioned me to you before...
ไม่เคยพูดถึงหนูให้คุณพ่อคุณแม่ฟังเลยเหรอ
No... That's not it...
ปะ เปล่าจ้ะ
He hinted me before.
เขาเคยบอกเป็นนัย ๆ
I was the one who didn't get the hint.
แต่น้าไม่เข้าใจเองแหละ
I must have said something
น้าคงพูดอะไร
that made him misunderstood me.
ที่ทำให้เขาเข้าใจผิด ใช่ไหม
It's just a misunderstanding.
เข้าใจผิดน่ะ
Jingjing.
จิงจิง
I really like you.
น้าชอบหนูมากนะ
I've never missed an episode
ละครที่หนูแสดงน่ะ
of the dramas that you're in.
น้าดูทุกตอนเลย
I know
น้ารู้ว่า
you two were classmates in high school.
หนูเป็นเพื่อนม.ปลายของอวี่ถู
But I never thought you two would...
แค่คิดไม่ถึงว่าหนูกับเขา
Uhm...
เอ่อ
Let's not just stand here.
อย่ามัวแต่ยืนอยู่ตรงนี้เลย
Let's go into the house. Go in and chat.
รีบเข้าบ้านก่อน เข้าบ้านกัน
Let me take a call.
น้ารับโทรศัพท์ก่อนนะ
Hello.
ฮัลโหล
You guys are here?
ถึงแล้วเหรอ
Yes. Yes.
ใช่ ๆ
It's the junction in front.
ตรงแยกข้างหน้าน่ะ
It's right after you turn in the junction.
เลี้ยวเข้ามาก็ถึงแล้ว
Yes. Yes.
ใช่ ๆ
Okay. See you in a while.
โอเค เดี๋ยวเจอกัน
Mom.
แม่ครับ
We would like to
ตอนนี้พวกเรา
keep it low for now.
ยังไม่อยากให้คนรู้เยอะ
Jingjing hasn't had her breakfast yet.
จิงจิงยังไม่ได้กินข้าวเช้า
I'll take her out for breakfast.
ผมจะพาเขาไปหาอะไรกินหน่อย
Okay. Okay.
ไปสิไป
Happy Lunar New Year!
คุณน้าคะ สุขสันต์วันตรุษจีนนะคะ
Eat more!
กินเยอะ ๆ นะ
I'll keep the secret for you two!
น้าจะเก็บเป็นความลับแน่
It tastes so good!
อร่อยจังเลย
(Mom)
(แม่)
Yu Tu.
อวี๋ถู
Mom.
แม่
Your grandaunt
ป้าของลูกน่ะ
wants to hang out at our place until afternoon.
ช่วงบ่ายพวกเขาจะมาเที่ยวบ้านเรา
Why don't we ask Jingjing to come tonight?
ตอนดึกเราชวนเฉียวจิงจิงมาดีไหม
Tell me.
ลูกบอกแม่มา
Is Qiao Jingjing
ว่าเฉียวจิงจิง
really your girlfriend?
เป็นแฟนลูกจริงหรือเปล่า
Mom.
แม่
Didn't you see everything already?
แม่ก็เห็นแล้วไม่ใช่เหรอ
I just want to confirm it again.
แม่ก็แค่อยากถามให้แน่ใจ
Let's see when she is free
ลูกดูซิว่าเขาสะดวกมา
to come to our house.
บ้านเราตอนกี่โมง
Ask her
ลองถามเขาดู
whether she's free tomorrow at noon.
พรุ่งนี้ตอนเที่ยงได้ไหม
We'll treat her to a meal.
พวกเราชวนเธอมากินข้าว
Mom, the thing is
คืองี้ครับ แม่
she has to rush back to Shanghai this afternoon
บ่ายวันนี้ เธอต้องรีบกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้
and back to her drama shoot
พรุ่งนี้เช้าตรู่
tomorrow morning.
ต้องรีบไปถ่ายละคร
How about this?
เอางี้ไหมครับ
Wait till when she comes back for her holiday next time.
ไว้รอวันหยุดครั้งต่อไป
I see.
งั้นเหรอ
What a shame.
น่าเสียดายจัง
It's all your fault.
ต้องโทษลูกนั่นแหละ
Not only did you not tell us
ดูซิ คบสาว
that you have a girlfriend,
ไม่ยอมบอกพ่อกับแม่เลย
you even talked nonsense
แถมยังพูดจาซี้ซั้ว
in front of her,
ให้เธอฟังอีก
ruining your parents' image.
ทำให้ภาพพจน์พ่อกับแม่เสียหมด
Are your dad and I that kind of people?
พ่อกับแม่ใช่คนแบบนั้นที่ไหนกัน
I haven't even told your dad yet.
แม่ยังไม่ได้บอกให้พ่อรู้นะ
You just wait until he finds out about this.
รอดูเถอะว่าพ่อจะจัดการลูกยังไง
Mom.
แม่
I was wrong.
ผมผิดไปแล้ว
I know.
ผมรู้แล้ว
You must tell her that
แต่ลูกต้องบอกจิงจิง
you were the one
ว่าลูกน่ะ
who was imagining things all this time.
คิดเพ้อเจ้อไปเอง
It has nothing to do with us.
พ่อกับแม่ไม่ได้พูดอย่างนั้น
We would always
พ่อกับแม่
welcome her to our house with open hands.
ต้อนรับจิงจิงมาที่นี่เสมอ
We all like her
พวกเราทุกคนชอบเธอมาก
very much.
ชอบมากจริง ๆ
Mom.
แม่
She already knows.
เธอรู้แล้ว
Sure.
โอเคลูก
You two enjoy yourselves.
เที่ยวให้สนุกนะ
Mom, I'll hang up now.
แค่นี้นะครับแม่
Okay. Okay.
โอเค ๆ
I feel that
ฉันคิดว่า
my parents
พ่อแม่ฉัน
wouldn't like you?
คงไม่ชอบเธองั้นเหรอ
This way, your mom
แบบนี้แม่นายจะได้
wouldn't have a problem with me.
ไม่ติดอกติดใจเรื่องฉันไง
Who asked you to
ใครบอกให้นาย
create a negative image for me before this?
ไปสร้างภาพเสีย ๆ ให้ฉันแบบนั้นล่ะ
Not bad.
ไม่เลวนะ
It's a pretty good idea.
ไอเดียนี้ดี
Right?
ใช่ไหมล่ะ ๆ
Was I quick with my response?
ฉันไหวพริบดีไหมล่ะ
Yes.
ดี
I need to learn from you.
ฉันจะเอาอย่างเธอบ้าง
It's the EQ that I've trained up
นี่เป็นอีคิวที่ฉันฝึกมา
after all these years of
จากการถูกสัมภาษณ์
variety shows and interviews.
ตอนออกรายการวาไรตี้มานานหลายปี
Where should
นี่พวกเรา
we go after this?
จะไปเที่ยวไหนเนี่ย
Let's go to Hufu.
หูฟู่แล้วกัน
I only covered half of the place the other day.
เมื่อวานซืนฉันเพิ่งเดินไปได้ครึ่งเดียว
Are we going to ride a boat?
เราจะนั่งเรือกันเหรอ
You'll be steering it?
นายขับใช่ไหม
Do you know how to steer it?
นายขับเป็นเหรอ
Then...
แล้ว
Do you really know how to steer?
แล้วนายขับเป็นจริง ๆ เหรอ
Yes.
เป็นสิ
Come.
มา
Put on the life vest.
ใส่เสื้อชูชีพก่อน
I don't really trust you.
ฉันไม่ค่อยเชื่อใจนายเท่าไหร่
You have no choice but to trust me.
ไม่เชื่อไม่ได้หรอก
You're already on my boat now.
เพราะเธออยู่บนเรือแล้ว
Hurry and put it on too.
นายก็ใส่ด้วยสิ
Are you ready to go?
พร้อมออกจากท่าหรือยัง
You really know how to steer!
นายขับเป็นจริง ๆ ด้วย
This is amazing!
สุดยอดเลย
The one in front!
ด้านหน้านั่นน่ะ
Go there!
ไปตรงนั้น
Why did you stop?
หยุดทำไมล่ะ
I can't go any further.
เครื่องดับน่ะ
Let's fuel up.
เติมน้ำมันก่อน
♪That nervous but sweet moment♪
♪ความหวังกับความหวานครั้งนั้น♪
♪I can entrust my heart in your hands♪
♪ให้ใจทั้งใจไว้ที่เธอคนเดียว♪
♪Missing that moment, missing someone♪
♪โลภบ้างเป็นบางเวลา อยากรักคนบางคน♪
♪Every memory with you♪
♪ทุกช่วงเวลาที่มีเธอ♪
♪Yes, yes, yes♪
♪เยส เยส เยส♪
♪Right in your world, right next to you♪
♪ในโลกของเธอ อยู่ข้างกายเธอ♪
It's full now.
เต็มถังแล้ว
♪Hold me closer and a little tighter♪
♪กอดอีกสักครั้ง กอดให้แน่นกว่านี้♪
Let's go.
ไปต่อล่ะ
♪The end of loneliness comes when I have joy of your company♪
♪สิ้นสุดความเดียวดาย ความสุขในการอยู่ใกล้เธอ♪
♪I'll be there for you every day♪
♪ทุกวันที่เธอมีฉัน♪
♪My heart is yours♪
♪ใจของฉันนั้นเป็นของเธอ♪
♪Baby, my heart is yours♪
♪ที่รัก ใจฉันเป็นของเธอ♪
♪Falling in love with you♪
♪จมลงในห้วงความรักกับเธอ♪
♪My heart is yours♪
♪ใจของฉันนั้นเป็นของเธอ♪
♪Baby, my heart is yours♪
♪ที่รัก ใจฉันเป็นของเธอ♪
♪Loving you♪
♪รักเธอ♪
♪Falling in love with you♪
♪จมลงในห้วงความรักกับเธอ♪
Later in the afternoon,
ช่วงบ่ายให้ทำตาม
let's stick to what we've planned before
วิธีที่บอกไว้
and say that I, your ex-classmate in high school,
ให้บอกว่าฉันเป็นเพื่อนม.ปลาย
am here to pick you up. Am I right?
เวลาไปรับเธอใช่ไหม
Yup.
ใช่
Once I'm done with my act,
เดี๋ยวฉันเล่นบทฉันจบ
I'll let you know.
แล้วจะบอกให้นายรู้
Sure. I'll wait for your contact.
ได้ ฉันจะรอสัญญาณ
I'll get going then.
งั้นฉันไปก่อนนะ
Here.
อะ
Old man.
ตาแก่
Eat more.
กินเยอะ ๆ ลูก
Okay.
ค่ะ
Dad, Mom.
พ่อคะ แม่คะ
Once I'm done eating,
หนูกินข้าวเสร็จ
I'll need to get back to Shanghai.
ต้องกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้แล้วนะ
What's the rush?
จะรีบร้อนไปทำไม
That's good too.
ก็ดี
It gets dark earlier in winter.
ฤดูหนาวฟ้ามืดไว
Plus, it's snowing outside.
แถมข้างนอกก็มีหิมะ
It's safer to go back earlier.
กลับเร็วหน่อย ปลอดภัยกว่า
When is your driver coming?
คนขับรถจะมากี่โมง
He can't come today.
พี่เขามาไม่ได้แล้วค่ะ
I'll be driving back myself.
หนูจะขับกลับเอง
What?
อะไรนะ
- You can't!
- ไม่ได้เด็ดขาด
Why can't I?
ทำไมไม่ได้ล่ะคะ
Although I don't drive a lot,
ถึงหนูขับรถไม่บ่อย
my skill is not bad.
แต่ฝีมือหนูก็ไม่เลวนะ
I even drove out
วันนี้หนูยังขับ
to hang out with Peipei today, didn't I?
ไปหาเพ่ยเพ่ยเลย
I haven't told you off about that yet,
แม่ยังไม่ได้ว่าอะไรสักหน่อย
and you dare to bring it up yourself.
ลูกยังพูดออกมาได้
Tell me.
ดูซิปีปีหนึ่ง
How many times do you even drive in a year?
ลูกขับรถเองกี่ครั้ง
Plus, that's in the city.
อีกอย่างขับในเมือง
There's no snow on the road.
บนถนนมันไม่มีหิมะ
Who knows what can happen
ถ้าขับทางไกล
when you drive long-distance.
มันเสี่ยงนะลูก
No way. You can't.
ไม่ได้ แม่ไม่ให้ขับ
That driver of yours...
คนขับรถลูกนี่ไม่ไหวเลย
Why is he not here?
ทำไมมาไม่ได้ล่ะ
His plane ticket was canceled
เที่ยวบินถูกยกเลิกน่ะค่ะ
and he couldn't get any tickets last minute.
หาซื้อตั๋วไม่ได้
You...
คุณ
How about this?
เอางี้นะ
Get her cousin brother to send her back.
ให้น้องชายไปส่งแล้วกัน
If he can't, I'll send you.
ถ้าไม่ได้ พ่อไปส่งเอง
Either way,
ไม่ว่ายังไง
you can't drive back yourself.
ลูกก็ห้ามขับเอง
That's so troublesome.
ไม่ต้องยุ่งยากขนาดนั้นค่ะ
I can drive back on my own.
หนูขับกลับเองได้
No means no.
ไม่ได้ก็คือไม่ได้
There's no room for discussion about this.
เรื่องนี้ไม่ต้องพูดแล้ว
Exactly.
ใช่
You don't have to worry
ไม่ต้องห่วงแล้วค่ะ
or trouble my cousin brother anymore.
แล้วก็ไม่ต้องกวนน้องชายด้วย
Just so happens, my ex-classmate
มีเพื่อนม.ปลายคนหนึ่ง
sent a message in the chatroom,
แชทในกลุ่มเพื่อนว่า
saying he'll be going back to Shanghai today.
วันนี้จะกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้พอดีเลย
Plus, he's been driving for a long time.
แถมเขายังขับรถเก่งด้วย
Really?
จริงเหรอ
Coming!
มาแล้ว ๆ
What a cold day today.
วันนี้หนาวจริง ๆ
Coming.
มาแล้วจ้ะ
Good afternoon.
สวัสดีครับคุณน้า
You are Jingjing's ex-classmate.
เธอคือเพื่อนจิงจิงใช่ไหม
Hurry.
เข้ามา ๆ
Come in and have some water.
รีบเข้ามา ดื่มน้ำก่อน
She's almost done.
จิงจิง ใกล้เสร็จแล้ว
Mom!
แม่
There's no need to drink.
ไม่ต้องให้ดื่มน้ำหรอก
Hurry!
เร็วหน่อย
We'll go now.
เดี๋ยวพวกเราออกเดินทางเลย
Hurry up.
เร็วหน่อย ๆ
This kid...
ลูกคนนี้นี่
How can you be so thoughtless?
ทำไมไม่มีมารยาทเลย
It's so cold today.
อากาศหนาวแบบนี้
You can go after having something warm.
ดื่มน้ำอุ่น ๆ ก่อนแล้วค่อยไป
Exactly.
ใช่ ๆ
It won't hold you guys up for too long.
ไม่ต้องกลัวว่าจะไปช้าหรอกนะ
Come. Have a seat inside.
รีบไปนั่งในบ้านก่อน
Yes.
ใช่ ๆ
Mr. and Mrs. Qiao.
คุณอา คุณน้า
It's okay.
ไม่เป็นไรหรอกครับ
There will probably be
ต่อไป
more chances in the future.
ยังมีโอกาสอีกเยอะครับ
Hurry, let's go.
รีบไปกันเถอะ
Actually, I'm Jingjing's boyfriend.
ที่จริงผมเป็นแฟนของจิงจิงครับ
We've been in a relationship for a long time.
พวกเราคบกันมานานแล้ว
But she always refused
แต่เธอไม่ยอม
to bring me to see you
พาผมมาพบคุณพ่อคุณแม่
and told me to say that
แถมยังให้ผม
we're just ex-classmates.
บอกว่าเป็นแค่เพื่อนม.ปลาย
What's going on?
- นี่มันอะไรกัน
♪I dreamed of starlight pulling the sleeves♪
♪ฉันฝันเห็นแสงดาวระยิบระยับ บนชายแขนเสื้อ♪
♪A white top covering the thin shoulders♪
♪ชุดสีขาว ปกคลุมหัวไหล่อันซูบเซียว♪
♪I have seen the wounds healed with each passing year♪
♪ฉันเห็นกาลเวลาเยียวยาบาดแผลได้♪
♪There will always be people running towards eternity♪
♪อย่างไรก็มีคนไล่ตามชั่วฟ้าดินสลาย♪
♪The bustling intersection♪
♪ท่ามกลางทางแยกผู้คนพลุกพล่าน♪
♪Looking back all of a sudden under the dim light♪
♪แสงไฟริบหรี่ เหลียวหลังมองไป♪
♪I loved your eyes looking at the starry sky♪
♪เคยรักเธอ มองไปยังดาวทอประกายบนฟากฟ้า นัยน์ตาที่สงบนิ่ง♪
♪And I loved the universe in your heart♪
♪ก็เคยรักเธอ ในใจฉันเธอคือทุกอย่าง ในจักรวาล♪
♪Time does not stop, remember the time that we failed to treasure♪
♪กาลเวลาไม่เคยหยุดรอ เก็บซ่อนความเสียใจในสิ่งที่ทำไปตลอดเวลา♪
♪The wind passes by the tall buildings with no one awaiting it♪
♪ลมพัดผ่านตึกสูง ไม่มีใครเฝ้ารออีกต่อไป♪
♪I've dreamed of traveling around the planet♪
♪ฉันก็เคยคิดฝันท่องไปตามดวงดาว♪
♪Seeing the galaxy pass through the clouds♪
♪ผ่านมวลเมฆ ดูทางช้างเผือกที่หลั่งไหล♪
♪I looked at the hills with sorrow♪
♪ฉันเคยมองขุนเขาอย่างเศร้าหมอง♪
♪Will the exit of the dream lead to the end of the starry sky?♪
♪ทางออกแห่งฝัน อยู่ที่สุดขอบทะเลดาวหรือไม่♪
♪Looking back all of a sudden♪
♪เหลียวหลังมองไป♪
♪Which galaxy am I drifting on?♪
♪ฉันล่องลอยอยู่บนทะเลดาวสายไหนกัน♪
♪Looking into the distance, which of the stars are your eyes?♪
♪เฝ้ามองว่าดาวดวงไหนคือนัยน์ตาเธอ♪
♪It's out of reach, so dazzling and hard to get♪
♪ดาวระยิบระยับ เอื้อมไม่ถึงครอบครองไม่ได้♪
♪Time does not hold back, the spring and autumn in the passing time♪
♪กาลเวลาไม่รอใคร เมื่อเวลาผ่าน สรรพสิ่งก็เปลี่ยนไป อดีตจบสิ้นลง♪
♪The wind sings the song of freedom as I listen to the tenderness of time♪
♪สายลมขับร้องอิสรภาพ ฉันตั้งใจฟังความอ่อนโยนของกาลเวลา♪